Guide to the Stanford University, Physical Sciences Program, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Physical Sciences Program, records
1931-1973
SC0169
Stanford University. Physical Sciences Program.
2.5 Linear feet
Collection pertains both to the School of Physical Sciences and the later program in physical sciences. Included are correspondence, budgets, fiscal records, and miscellaneous items, 1934-72; one file on courses, 1931-32; course materials for the general program classes (survey of physical sciences and astronomy), 1952-73; and course materials for several physics classes, 1955-65. Collection also includes a file on the campus observatory, 1960-64.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer 1977.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The School of Physical Sciences, instituted in 1926, consisted of the departments of chemistry, geology, mathematics, and physics; in 1949 the School of Humanities and Sciences was organized and retained a general program in physical sciences. The program was administered by chemistry professor Claudio Alvarez-Tostado.
Description of the Collection
Collection pertains both to the School of Physical Sciences and the later program in physical sciences. Included are correspondence, budgets, fiscal records, and miscellaneous items, 1934-72; one file on courses, 1931-32; course materials for the general program classes (survey of physical sciences and astronomy), 1952-73; and course materials for several physics classes, 1955-65. Collection also includes a file on the campus observatory, 1960-64.
Access Terms
Alvarez-Tostado, Claudio.; Stanford University. Observatory.; Stanford University. Physical Sciences Program.; Stanford University. School of Physical Sciences.; Physical sciences.; Science--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - General Files
    - Advisee placement, 1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Appointments of lab assistants, 1949-65 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1936-38 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1950 and 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re lab instructors, 1960-72 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Courses, 1931-32 and undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Courses 1, 2, 3, 50 – correspondence, 1955-66 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fiscal records, budget statements, 1934-45 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Fiscal records, budget statements, 1945-48 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fiscal records, miscellaneous, 1934-37 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Fiscal records, miscellaneous, 1938-46 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fiscal records, miscellaneous, 1946-48 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Fiscal records, miscellaneous, 1951-61 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Lab schedules and general material, 1966, 1972 and undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1964-70 and undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous T.A. material, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Observatory, 1960-64 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Undergraduate instructional scientific equipment, proposal, ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Courses
    - P.S. 1 [survey of physical sciences, with lab work], 1965-67 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - P.S. 1 handouts, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - P.S. 1 old exams, 1959-64 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - P.S. 1 labs, 1966-68 and undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - P.S. 1 labs 2-4, 1964-65 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - P.S. 1 labs 5-9, 1964-65 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - P.S. 2 [survey of physical sciences, with lab work], 1965-68 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - P.S. 2 handouts, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - P.S. 2 labs, 1965-66 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - P.S. 2 old exams, 1960-67 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - P.S. 2 stencils, 1963-64 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - P.S. 3 [survey of physical sciences, with lab work], 1966-68 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - P.S. 3 handouts, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - P.S. 3 labs, 1965-66 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - P.S. 3 old exams, 1952-60 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - P.S. 3 old exams, 1962-71 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - P.S. 3 labs, 1966 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - P.S. 5 [survey of physical sciences, no lab work], 1966-72 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - P.S. 6 [survey of physical sciences, no lab work], old exams, 1969-70 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - P.S. 6, 1972, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - P.S. 7 [survey of physical sciences, no lab work], 1966-72 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - P.S. 10, 1971-72 and n.d (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - P.S. 50 [astronomy], 1966, 1971 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - P.S. 100, 1971 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - P.S. 150, 1970-73 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Physics, miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Physics 51, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Physics 100, 1961-65 (Box 3, Folder 13)